我已在路上漂泊了几个月
I've been on the road for a couple of months.
你一个人吗
By yourself?
是啊
Yeah.
之前你住在哪里
Where did you live before that?
一座小镇上
I was in a town.
那里有这些怪物吗
Were the monsters there?
没有
No.
那里很安全
It was safe.
都是好人
Full of good people.
出什么事了
What happened?
他发疯了
He just lost it.
谁
Who?
掌管大权的人
The man in charge.
我差点死在那里
I barely got out alive.
你看上去就像差点死了
You look like you barely got out alive.
- 塔拉 - 我是说
- Tara. - I mean…
我们有点精神紧张
We're a little on edge.
我们一直躲在这里
We've been holed up in here.
等着国民警卫队 自从…
waiting for the National Guard since…
- 他妈的一切大乱开始 - 注意用词
- The shit hit the fan. - Language.
自从一切大乱开始
Since the crap hit the fan.
的确如此
Which it did.
然后就蔓延到了整个区域
right before it got flung all over the damn place.
你打算待在大楼里吗
Are you planning on staying in the building?
你到底打不打算留下来
Are you planning on staying or not?
- 该死 这是个哑巴 - 塔拉
- Holy shit, with the no talking. - Tara.
我妹问了你一个问题
My sister asked you a question.
只过一晚
Just for the night.
你看见这个了吗
You see this?
这是一把装满子弹的标配史密斯威森手枪
This here is a fully loaded, standard issue Smith & Wesson.
我是亚特兰大警察
I'm Atlanta City Police.
这里有足够的枪支弹药 可以在接下来十年里
and I have enough artillery in here to kill you.
每天杀死你一次
every day for the next 10 years.
你要是敢耍我或者我家人
You mess with me or my family,
我向耶稣发誓 我会干掉你的
and I swear to Christ, I will put you down.
懂吗
Got it?
懂了
Got it.
那我们就没事了
Then we're cool.
来击拳吧
Pound it.
给 哥们
Here, bro.
在你走之前 这个我们得留着
We'll hold onto this until you go.
是的
Yeah.
你叫什么名字
You got a name?
布莱恩
Brian.
布莱恩·赫里奥特
Brian Heriot.
你肯定饿了
You got to be hungry.
里面没什么更好的东西了
You're not gonna find anything better in there.
自从威尔海姆小姐去了佛罗里达
Tara ransacked the place.
塔拉就将那里洗劫一空
after Miss Wilhelm took off for Florida.
威尔海姆小姐最爱吃棉豆
Big fan of butter beans, Miss Wilhelm.
谢谢
Thank you.
…四 五
…four, five.
来吧 孩子 看看你的牌
Come on, kiddo. Show me what you got here.
一切还好吗
Everything okay?
她又开始不吃饭了
She didn't eat again.
她爱吃腌牛肉 试试那个
She likes the corned beef. Try that.
最后两罐我是留给老爸的
I'm saving the last two cans for Dad.
她不是挑食 只是害怕而已
She's not picky, she's terrified.
伙计 您悠着点可以吗
Why don't you slow down, buddy, all right?
这里又不是假日酒店
This ain't the Holiday Inn.
左侧的木桶是洗涤用水
Bucket on the left is for washing,
右侧是清水
right is for rinsing.
塔拉
Tara.
抱歉
Sorry.
你够吃吗
You get enough to eat?
我给你倒点咖啡
I'll get you some coffee.
坐吧
Sit down.
去那儿坐着
Right there. Go on.
再掷一次
Go ahead, roll again.
嘿 过来啊
Hey, come here.
你有香烟吗
You got a cigarette?
老爸 你的氧气筒
Dad, your oxygen tank.
你没看见警告标志吗
Do you not see that red sticker?
我们千辛万苦才活到现在
I'll be damned if a Merit Ultra Menthol is gonna blow this place up.
可不能因为你抽烟而把这地方炸掉
after all the work we've done to stay alive up here. Okay?
无所谓了 莉莉
It's all the same, Lily.
你能别这样说了吗
You can stop that talk right there.
不就是讨根烟吗
It's just a cigarette.
请自便
Help yourself.
我们的肉干够吃好几天
We got roni sticks for days.
说不定能撑几年
Years, probably.
看见外面停的大货车了吗
You see that big truck parked outside?
就是那辆戈贝利食品货车
Come on, dude, the Gorbelli food truck.
雷·查尔斯都可以看见（盲人歌手）
Ray Charles could have seen it.
是啊
Yeah.
老爸给他们开车
Dad drove for them.
即便是还背着氧气瓶
Even with the tank.
他们当时关闭了75号公路
The day they closed down the 75…
从「他-妈-的」天下大乱开始
When the S-H-I-T hit the fan.
他从学校接了梅根 到医院接了我
He grabbed Megan from school, picked me up at the hospital…
她还从医院里偷了几个氧气瓶
She stole a bunch of oxygen tanks from that dump.
接着我们仨一起去接塔拉
Then the three of us rushed over to get Tara.
我当时在警局上班 登记犯人
I was at the station working, booking.
那时一片混乱
With everything going on,
行尸袭来 军队进驻亚特兰大
the attacks, the Army going into Atlanta,
他一直让我们和他寸步不离
he wasn't about to let us out of his sight.
还好我们走运 老爸的货车里囤满了
Lucky for us, the old man's truck was pretty much stocked.
堆到天花板的意面圈
floor to ceiling with sketti rings,
火鸡辣酱汤 还有这些零食
turkey chili, and these little suckers.
小梅 爷爷得休息一下了 好吗
Meggie, Granddad needs a break, okay?
- 莉莉 - 来了 爸爸
- Lily. - Sure, Daddy.
数到三
On three.
大个子 过来搭把手吧
A little help here, big guy.
来
Here.
好吧 叫的不是你
Oh, right. No, not you.
是屋里的另外一个大个子
The other big guy in the room.
塔拉
Tara.
行了
Okay.
数到三
On three.
好的 一 二
Okay, one, two…
这里
Here. Here.
听到那些东西了么
You hear them?
听到了
Yeah.
能抬一下我的腿吗 朋友
Get my legs, friend?
塔拉上去了好几次
Tara's been up there a bunch of times.
把那些混球轰成碎片
blasting them bastards to pieces.
她说那些东西怎么也打不死
She says they just keep getting back up.
我告诉她别再上去了
I told her no more.
不能让她继续浪费子弹了
Can't afford to waste her bullets.
你有小孩吗
You got kids?
没有
No.
我的女儿们出生的时候
When my girls were born,
我终于明白了成为一个男人意味着什么
that's when I finally figured out what it was to be a man.
你懂的 一个真男人
You know, a real man.
你保护她们 保证她们安全
You protect them, you keep them safe.
你花尽心思让她们变得更强
You just try to make them stronger.
直到她们能照顾自己
until they can look out for themselves.
但这种情况
But… this here,
我从未想过她们会遇上这种事
I… I never counted on this.
我有个伙计
Hey, I got a buddy.
比尔·詹金斯 他住在303
Bill Jenkins, he lives up in 303.
他那儿有套很棒的双陆棋
He's got a real nice backgammon set up there.
他不会介意的 他把棋放在床底下
He won't mind and he keeps it under his bed there.
拜托了
Just… please.
你在外面生活过
You've been out there in the world.
你知道在那些东西周围如何自卫
and you know how to handle yourself around those things.
听着 我知道你也许不理解
Look, I know you might not understand it.
因为你没有女儿
'cause you don't got a baby girl of your own,
但是
but…
这东西也许能让我的梅根重新开始说话
it might be something that might make my Megan talk again.
拜托了
Please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
（一切都会过去）
给你上路带的东西
Couple things for the road.
我自己可以
I'm okay.
你帮了我们
You helped us.
这是我们的谢意
We're saying thank you.
你自己看着办吧
Deal with it.
我估计你需要这个
I guess you'll be needing this back.
你留着吧
Keep it.
别
Don't…
用那玩意儿扔我
throw that at me.
这是你的枪
It's your gun.
你可以拿回去
You can have it back.
你也需要一把
You need another one.
我有这个了
I have this.
塔拉说的没错
Tara was right.
我们应该搜你的身
We should have frisked you.
我在楼上发现的
I found it upstairs.
你留着那把吧
You keep that.
你们要命中脑袋才行
You have to kill the brain.
什么
What?
你姐姐冲着它们的身体射击
Your sister, she shot 'em in the body,
但你们得射这里
but you have to hit 'em here.
这样才能杀死它们
That's what kills them.
为什么
Why?
我有些事情得求你
I need to ask you something.
我爸的肺癌已经到晚期了
My dad's got stage four lung cancer.
我多年照顾肿瘤病人
I worked oncology for a few years.
能看出他快不行了
He's nearing the end.
他的氧气还剩两天的量
He's got about two days of oxygen.
也许更少
Maybe less.
我们从没想过他能挺这么久
We never thought he'd make it this long.
你已经为我们做了很多 但是…
You've already done so much for us, but…
几个街区之外
there's an old folks home.
有一家老人院
a couple of blocks from here.
哪怕只有一罐也行
Even one tank would mean everything.
他是唯一能让梅根微笑的人
He's the only one who can put a smile on Megan's face.
哪怕只有一秒也好
Even for a second.
这两个都是满的
They're both full.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
是的
Yeah.
你还没让我说谢谢呢
You didn't let me say thank you.
我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
坐吧
Sit.
让我重操旧业护理你
Let me be a nurse again.
好消息是你不需要缝针
Good news is it doesn't look like you need any stitches.
坏消息是
Bad news…
这会像狂蜂蜇了一样疼
this is gonna sting like a couple of angry bees.
有事做的感觉真好
Feels good to have something to do.
从来没人说起过
Nobody ever mentioned just.
世界末日竟然会这么无聊
how boring the end of the world was gonna be.
她以为你是她爸爸
She thought you were her dad.
梅根
Megan.
当她看见你在街上时
When she saw you out there on the street.
三年半前的一个晚上 他出了门
He went out one night about three and a half years ago.
去买几瓶啤酒和强力球彩票
to get a couple beers and a Powerball ticket.
他说他很快就回来
Said he'd be right back.
梅根把你认成了他
Megan thought you were him,
以为你终于回家了
finally coming right back.
- 妈妈 - 在这里 亲爱的
- Mama. - In here, honey.
一切都很好 甜心
Everything's okay, sweetheart.
布莱恩受了点小伤 需要清理一下
Brian just got a boo-boo that needs a little cleaning up.
就跟你被割伤时一样
Same as when you get a cut.
我没拿药膏
I don't have the ointment.
我去拿药 你帮我看护一下病人吧
Why don't you watch my patient until I get back?
好的
Okay.
你眼睛怎么了
What happened to your eye?
没了
It's gone.
出了什么事吗
Something happen to you.
还是你一生下来就这样
or were you just born like that?
出了事
Something happened to me.
我是不是不该问
Was that bad to ask?
没事
No.
我会告诉你我的眼睛怎么了
I'll tell you what happened to my eye,
但你得发誓保守秘密
but you have to promise to keep it secret.
我发誓
I promise.
那是什么意思
What's that?
拉钩上吊不许变
Pinkie swear.
发誓保密 否则不得好死
Plus cross my heart and hope to die.
好吧
Well…
我是个海盗
I'm a pirate.
不可能
No way.
被你识破了
Yeah, you caught me.
其实是我救人的时候出了事
What really happened was I was trying to help someone.
为了救我深爱的人
Someone I loved very much.
你怎么帮助他们的
How were you trying to help them?
我想尽力保护他们
I was trying to protect them, you know?
不让他们受伤
Stop them getting hurt.
但你自己却受伤了
But you got hurt instead.
是啊
Yeah.
他们也受伤了吗
Did they get hurt, too?
是啊 也受伤了
Yeah, yeah, they did.
我真遗憾
I'm sorry.
我也是
Me, too.
这是什么
What is it?
国际象棋
Chess.
看起来好难
Looks hard.
对有些人来说可能会难 但你很聪明
Well, maybe for some folks, but you're smart.
你很快就能学会
You'll catch on quick.
这个棋子叫什么
What's this one called?
那是卒
That's a pawn.
他们是你的士兵
They're your soldiers.
他们会死吗
Do they die?
有时会
Sometimes.
如果他们都死了 你就输了吗
Do you lose if they die?
不 不一定
No, not necessarily.
就算你折损了很多小卒
You can lose a lot of soldiers,
还是可以翻盘
but still win the game.
那是国王
That's the king.
你要想办法俘获他
That's the guy you want to capture.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你等着瞧吧
You'll see.
像你
Looks like you.
是啊
Yeah.
好了 来下棋吧
Come on, let's play.
这些是卒
So these ones are pawns.
他去世了
He's gone.
我想他去世有一会儿了
I think he's been gone a while.
你们应该离开这里
Y'all should go now.
给我们点时间
Just give us a minute.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, Daddy.
塔拉
Tara!
- 住手 你在干什么 - 那不是爸爸
- Stop! What are you doing? - It's not Dad!
- 快住手 - 它不是爸爸
- Stop! - It's not Dad!
我懂 好吗
I know, okay?
这种事迟早会发生
It happens no matter what?
是的
Yeah.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
他也许会咬到我
He could have got me.
差点就咬到我了
He almost got me.
我在想
I was thinking.
如果他还在 一定会很感激你
he would have been grateful or whatever.
及时制止了他
that you stopped him, from him…
你懂我的意思吗
you know what I mean?
所以 我们没闹翻
So, yeah, we're cool.
再见
Good-bye.
不
No.
- 我们要跟你一起去 - 不行
- We're coming with you. - No.
肯定有更安全的地方
There has to be someplace better,
你要帮我们找到
and you're gonna help us find it.
- 莉莉 - 我看到照片了 布莱恩
- Lily. - I saw the picture, Brian.
你曾有家人 我知道
You had a family, I know that.
我也知道我们不是她们
And I know we're not them.
但就现在来说 你必须跟我们在一起
But for now, you're stuck with us.
- 只有这一个办法 - 我不能这样
- And that's just the way it's gonna be. - I can't.
你已经这样了
You already have.
我们该去哪儿
Where should we go?
计划赶不上变化
No use making a plan.
我们只能看着它们走
We'll go where they let us.
它们是谁
Who's they?
道路
The roads.
行尸
The biters.
我其实不算是警察
I'm not really a cop.
但也不全是谎话
I mean, it's not a total lie.
我是警校学生
I was in the academy.
抱歉对你说谎了
I'm sorry I lied to you.
你不必感到抱歉
You don't have to be sorry.
我确实很抱歉
Well, I am.
你觉得我们能活下去吗
Do you think we can make it?
我们能的
We'll make it.
你在骗我吗
Are you lying to me?
没有
No.
你可以过来 梅根
You can come join us, Megan.
过段时间就好了
It's just gonna take some time.
没事
It's okay.
我们很快就能找到车
We'll find another car soon.
但愿你是对的
I hope you're right.
这乡村景色总是让我想起萨姆
This whole country backdrop is reminding me of Sam.
- 又来了 - 我以为她是我的真命天女
- Here we go. - I thought she was the one.
然后你们去野营 吃了致幻蘑菇 全完了
Then you went camping, ate mushrooms, game over.
你忘记了
You're forgetting the part where.
萨姆崩溃了 然后告诉我她有男朋友
Sam broke down and told me she had a boyfriend,
她其实不喜欢妹子
that she wasn't really into chicks.
那是我一生中最糟糕的周末
Ugh, worst weekend of my life.
塔拉
Tara.
天呐 该死
Oh, man. Damn it!
- 你还好吗 - 我没事
- You all right? - I'm fine.
- 塔拉 停下 让我看看 - 我没事
- Tara, stop. Let me look at it. - I'm fine!
把背包给我 我没事
Just hand me my backpack. I'm fine. I'm fine.
- 你能走路吗 - 可以 我很好
- Can you walk? - Yeah, I'm fine.
我没事 走吧
I'm fine. Let's go.
丢下包 我们走 快
Drop your bags. Let's go. Come on.
- 梅根 - 梅根 快点
- Megan. - Megan, come on.
梅根 现在快走
Megan, right now. Come on.
- 梅根 - 快啊 梅根
- Megan! - Come on, Megan.
梅根 快走
Megan, come on.
梅根 快点走啊
Megan, right now. Come on.
来吧 梅根 来吧
Come on, Megan. Come on.
梅根
Megan!
来
Here.
快来
Come on.
走
Go.
快跑
Move.
- 布莱恩 - 我在
- Brian! - I'm here.
对不起 你还好吗
I'm sorry. You okay?
还好吗
You all right?
我不会让任何事伤害你
I'm never gonna let anything happen to you.
好吗
Okay?
- 你发誓 - 我发誓
- Promise? - Cross my heart.
活见鬼了
Holy shit.
我发誓
Cross my heart.